<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rv178</title>
    <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rv178</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 15:20:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rv178.github.io/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Build Automation Tool</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/writing-a-build-automation-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 15:20:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/writing-a-build-automation-tool/</guid>
      <description>After using GNU Make for automating the build step in my projects, I had this idea of making my own build automation tool like Make.
I originally wanted to use Makefile-like syntax for the config file but instead settled with TOML after thinking about it for a while. I also used Rust to write this since I am kinda familiar with the language.
Rust has a TOML crate for parsing TOML files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FEN String Parsing in Rust</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/fen-string-parsing-in-rust/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 14:54:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/fen-string-parsing-in-rust/</guid>
      <description>I finally finished the FEN string parsing part of my chess engine after days of procrastinating and I just wanted to share my experience with everyone.
So a FEN string looks like this:
rnbqkbnr/pppppppp/8/8/8/8/PPPPPPPP/RNBQKBNR w KQkq - 0 1 This is the FEN string of the starting position in standard chess. It looks like random crap at first glance but this string conveys a lot of information.
So let&amp;rsquo;s divide it into parts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Chess</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/learning-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 12:10:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/learning-chess/</guid>
      <description>So a while ago after being absolutely destroyed by a friend in a game of chess, I decided to actually learn the game.
What&amp;rsquo;s chess? Chess is a popular game of strategy where two players play against each other. It involves a chess board containing 64 squares and 16 pieces on each side.
The players have a pair of rooks, bishops and knights. They also have eight pawns, a queen and a king.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A brief recap of my Linux journey up until now</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/my-linux-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 09:47:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/posts/my-linux-journey/</guid>
      <description>So hi! I have been using Linux for almost 5 months now and I have learned a lot! Just wanted to share my experience with everyone.
When I asked my friend (who is an expert in Linux), he recommended me Pop!_OS, an Ubuntu based distro. So, I installed it and it was my first Linux distribution. My experience using Pop!_OS was amazing and it still is one of my favourite distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/about/</guid>
      <description>about</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find</title>
      <link>https://rv178.github.io/website/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rv178.github.io/website/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
